Guide to the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Division of Intercourse and Education
  The records of the Division consist of general correspondence (1910-1934); topical volumes (1910-1940), which comprise records of the Division that were bound by Endowment staff into volumes covering general categories; the Division's office files on the European Centre, London office, and Geneva Research Center; and the manuscripts of the lectures sponsored by the European Centre (the Cours).
  Series III. is organized into the following subseries:
  B. Topical volumes
  C. European Centre
  D. London Office
  - Subseries III.A: General correspondence, 1910-1934
    (44 vols)
    - 1910-1911 (Volume 34-35)
    - 1912 (Volume 36-37)
    - 1913 (Volume 38-41)
    - 42-451914 (Volume Vol)
    - 1915 (Volume 46-48)
    - 1916 (Volume 49)
    - 1917 (Volume 50)
    - 1918 (Volume 51)
    - 1919 (Volume 52)
    - 1920 (Volume 53-54)
    - 1921 (Volume 55-56)
    - 1922 (Volume 57-58)
    - 1923 (Volume 59)
    - 1924 (Volume 60-61)
    - 1925 (Volume 62-63)
    - 1926 (Volume 64-65)
    - 1927 (Volume 66)
    - 1928 (Volume 67)
    - 1929 (Volume 68-69)
    - 1930 (Volume 70-71)
    - 1931 (Volume 72-73)
    - 1932 (Volume 74-75)
    - 1933 (Volume 76)
    - 1934 (Volume 77)
  - Subseries III.B: Topical volumes, 1910-1940
    (174 volumes)
    Material related to the topics covered by these volumes May be found throughout the collection. See especially Series III.C., III.D., V., VI., and VII.
    These volumes are not indexed unless noted.
    - Miscellaneous requests and suggestions, 1910-1911 (5 vols)(Indexed)
      - A-F (Volume 78)
      - G-K (Volume 79)
      - L-Q (Volume 80)
      - R-Z (Volume 81)
      - Supplement (Volume 82)
    - American Association for International Conciliation, 1911-1922
      - 1911-1914 (Volume 83)
      - 1915 (Volume 84)
      - 1916 (Volume 85)
      - 1917 (Volume 86)
      - 1918 (Volume 87)
      - 1918-1920 (Volume 88)
      - 1922 (Volume 89)
      - Inter-American Division, 1918-1919 (Volume 90-91)
      - Pan American Division, 1915-1917 (Volume 92-93)
    - American Peace Society
      - 1911-1912 (Volume 94)
      - 1913-1919 (Volume 95)
    - Angell's "The Great Illusion", 1911-1916 (Volume 96)
    - Applications for Employment in Europe, 1911-1918 (Volume 97)
    - Apllication for Employment in the Americas, 1911-1918 (Volume 98)
    - Applications for subventions in the Western Hemisphere, 1911-1922
      - 1911-1912 (Volume 99)
      - 1912 (Volume 100)
      - 1913 (Volume 101)
      - 1914 (Volume 102)
      - 1915 (Volume 103-104)
      - 1916 (Volume 105)
      - 1917 (Volume 106-107)
      - 1918 (Volume 108)
      - 1918-1921 (Volume 109)
      - 1921-1922 (Volume 110)
    - Applications for subventions outside America, 1911-1922
      - 1911-1912 (Volume 111)
      - 1912 (Volume 112)
      - 1913 (Volume 113)
      - 1914 (Volume 114)
      - 1915 (Volume 115)
      - 1916 (Volume 116)
      - 1917-1918 (Volume 117)
      - 1919-1920 (Volume 118)
      - 1921-1922 (Volume 119)
    - Arbitration treaties, 1911-1912 (Volume 120)
    - The Arbitrator (London), 1914-1918 (Volume 163)
    - American League to limit Armaments, 1915-1916 (Volume 195)
    - Balkan Commission, 1913-1915 (Volume 121)
    - Bureau permanent de la Paiz Berne, 1911-1920 (Volume 122)
    - Canadian Branch of Conciliation Internationale, 1912-1913 (Volume 195)
    - Andrew Carnegie, 1913-1919 (Volume 123)
    - Chinese affairs, 1911-1918 (Volume 124)
    - Church Peace Union, 1913-1919 (Volume 164)
    - Concord, 1915-1916 (Volume 163)
    - Cosmos, 1917-1919 (Volume 125)
    - Courses on International relations, 1916-1918 (Volume 126)
    - d'Estournelles, Baron. Letters, 1914-1922
      - Aug 1914-June 1915 (Spine labeled vol I) (Volume 127)
      - June -Nov 1915 (Spine labeled vol II) (Volume 128)
      - Nov 1915-June 1916 (Spine labeled vol III) (Volume 129)
      - June 1916-Dec 1916 (Spine labeled vol IV) (Volume 130)
      - Dec 1916-Apr 1917 (Spine labeled vol V) (Volume 131)
      - May -Jun 1917 (Spine labeled vol VI) (Volume 132)
      - Vol VII and Vol VIII, Jun 1917-Jul 1918 (Missing) (Volume 133-134)
      - Jul-Dec 1918 (Spine labeled vol IX) (Volume 135)
      - Dec 1918-Mar 1919 (Spine labeled vol X) (Volume 136)
      - Vol XI through Vol XIV, Mar 1919-Aug 1920 (Missing) (Volume 138-140)
      - Aug-Dec 1920 (Spine labeled vol XV) (Volume 141)
      - Dec 1920-Mar 1921 (Spine labeled vol XVI) (Volume 142)
      - Mar-June 1921 (Spine labeled vol XVII) (Volume 143)
      - June -Nov 1921 (Spine labeled vol XVIII) (Volume 144)
      - Nov-Dec 1921 (Spine labeled vol XIX) (Volume 145)
      - Dec 1921-Jan 1922 (Spine labeled vol XX) (Volume 146)
      - Jan-Apr 1922 (Spine labeled vol XXI) (Volume 147)
    - Division of Economics and History, 1911-1918 (Volume 148)
    - Division of International Law, 1911-1915 (Volume 149)
    - Die Friedens Warte, 1912-1913 (Volume 163)
    - Great Britain-Special Subjects, 1911-1923
      - 1911-1913 (Volume 150)
      - 1914-1919 (Disbound and housed in archival box) (Volume 151)
      - 1919-1920 (Volume 152)
      - 1920-1923 (Volume 153)
    - Herald of Peace, 1912-1917 (Volume 163)
    - Institute of International Education, 1918-1923
      - 1918 (Volume 154)
      - 1919-1920 (Volume 155)
      - 1920-1923 (Volume 156)
    - International Conciliation in Great Britain, 1912-1917 (Volume 157)
    - International Polity Clubs, 1915 (Volume 195)
    - Japan Educational Exchange, 1911-1920
      - 1911-1913 (Volume 158)
      - 1914 (Volume 159)
      - 1914-1916 (Volume 160)
      - 1917-1918 (Volume 161)
      - 1918-1920 (Volume 162)
    - La Paix par le droit, 1912-1919 (Volume 163)
    - Lake Mohonk Conference, 1913-1917 (Volume 164)
    - Latin American Educational Exchange, 1911-1920
      - 1911-1912 (Volume 165)
      - 1912-1914 (Disbound and housed in archival box) (Volume 166)
      - 1914 (Volume 167)
      - 1915 (Volume 168)
      - 1916 (Volume 169)
      - 1917-1918 (Volume 170)
      - 1918-1920 (Volume 171)
    - League to Enforce Peace, 1915-1918 (Volume 195)
    - Lectures in the United States, 1915-1916
      - 1915 (Volume 172-176)
      - 1915-1916 (Volume 177)
    - L' office central Brussels, 1911-1922
      - 1911-1915 (Volume 178)
      - 1915-1922 (Volume 179)
    - Libraries for presentation, 1917-1922
      - 1917-1919 (Volume 180)
      - 1919-1922 (Volume 181)
    - New York Bureau accounts and miscellaneous, 1911-1922
      - 1911-1913 (Volume 182)
      - 1914 (Volume 183)
      - 1915 (Volume 184)
      - 1916 (Volume 185)
      - 1917 (Volume 186)
      - 1918 (Volume 187)
      - 1918-1919 (Volume 188)
      - 1919-1920 (Volume 189)
      - 1920-1921 (Volume 190)
      - 1921-1922 (Volume 191)
    - New York Peace Society, 1913-1919 (Volume 192)
    - One hundreth anniversary of Peace Between English Speking People, 1913-1922
      - 1913-1917 (Volume 193)
      - 1917-1922 (Volume 194)
    - Panama Canal Tolls
      - 1912-1914 (Volume 195)
    - Comments of trustees in Panama Canal tolls exemption, 1913 (Volume 196)
    - Paris Office Accounts, 1911-1921
      - 1911-1912 (Volume 197)
      - 1912 (Volume 198)
      - 1912-1913 (Volume 199)
      - 1913 (Volume 200)
      - 1913-1914 (Volume 201)
      - 1914 (Volume 202)
      - 1914-1915 (Volume 203)
      - 1915 (Volume 204)
      - 1915-1916 (Volume 205)
      - 1916-1917 (Volume 206)
      - 1917-1918 (Volume 207)
      - 1918-1919 (Volume 208)
      - 1919-1920 (Volume 209)
      - 1920-1921 (Volume 210)
    - Peter Day's Johannesburg, 1912 (Volume 163)
    - President Elliot's International Voyage, 1911-1913 (Volume 211)
    - Press Conferences, 1917-1918 (Volume 194)
    - Reports of Special Correspondents, 1911-1940
    - See also Series I.N. Reports for Trustees under correspondents' names and III.C.3 Representatives and Associated Personnel.
      - 1928-1929 (Volume 212)
      - 1931-1932 (Volume 213)
      - 1933-1934 (Volume 214)
      - 1935-1936 (Volume 215)
      - 1937 (Volume 216)
      - 1938 (Volume 217)
      - 1939-1940 (Volume 218)
    - W. J. Collins (See also volumes 224 and 225)
      - 1919-1920 (Volume 219)
      - 1920-1922 (Volume 220)
    - A.H. Fried
      - 1911-1913 (Volume 221)
      - 1914-1918 (Volume 222)
    - Eduardo Giretti
      - 1918-1919 (Volume 163)
      - 1919-1920 (Volume 223)
      - 1920-1922 (Volume 224)
    - F.W. Hirst and W.J. Collins
      - 1911-1915 (Volume 225)
      - 1916-1919 (Volume 226)
    - T. Miyaoka
      - 1912 (Volume 227-228)
      - 1913 (Volume 229)
      - 1914-1915 (Volume 230)
      - 1916 (Volume 231)
      - 1917 (Volume 232)
      - 1918 (Volume 233)
      - 1919-1920 (Volume 234)
      - 1920-1922 (Volume 235)
    - O. Nippold, 1920-1922 (Volume 236)
    - W. Patzkowski, 1911-1915 (Volume 237)
    - Trustees, 1911-1923
      - 1911-1917 (Volume 238)
      - 1917-1919 (Volume 239)
      - 1919-1921 (Volume 240)
      - 1921-1923 (Volume 241)
    - Union interparliamentaire Brussels, 1911-1919
      - 1911-1917 (Volume 242)
      - 1917-1919 (Volume 243)
    - Verband Internationale Verstandigung, 1912-1920
      - 1912-1915 (Volume 244)
      - 1915-1918 (Volume 245)
      - 1918-1920 (Volume 246)
    - World War, 1914-1921
      - 1914-1915 (Volume 247)
      - 1915-1916 (Volume 248)
      - 1916-1917 (Volume 249)
      - 1917-1921 (Volume 250)
    - World's Court League, 1916-1918 (Volume 164)
    - World Peace Foundation (Boston), 1913-1918 (Volume 251)
  - Subseries III.C: European Centre (Centre Européen)
    (74 boxes)
    An office of the Division of Intercourse and Education was established in Paris in 1912 with an Advisory Council composed of representative and distinguished statesmen and public leaders of Europe and Asia (Dotation Carnegie pour la Paix Internationale-Centre Européen). An Executive Committee that was in charge of carrying out the work of the Division abroad was appointed from the Advisory Council. Baron d'Estournelles de Constant was President of the Advisory Council from its formation until his death in 1924.
    Four Special Correspondents were appointed (nationals of Austria, England, Germany, and Japan) to keep the Division's director informed regarding international policies and international conduct relating to their respective countries. After World War I, the Advisory Council was reconstituted to include members from additional countries, and the number of Special Correspondents was increased to seven.
    The European Center was reorganized again in 1925 when it's administration was placed in charge of an American Directeur-Adjoint, with the advice of a consultative committee formed of members from various European countries. On June 1, 1939 this committee was dissolved, while the Directeur-Adjoint remained in charge.
    The Centre Européen actively participated in the work of the International Studies Conference, for which the Directeur-Adjoint served as executive chairman and the Institute of Intellectual Cooperation in Paris provided the secretariat. The European Centre also supported in part the Geneva Research Centre. (Source: Summary of Organization and Work, 1911-1941 (Washington DC: CEIP, 1941), pages 26-8.)
    These are the files on the European Centre kept by the Washington and New York offices. For the records of the European Centre (the Paris Office Files) and a full description of the European Centre's activities see CEIP Centre Européen Records also at the RBML.
    Subseries III.C. is organized into the following subseries:
    1. Executive Comittee Minutes
    2. Officers
    3. Representatives and Associated Personnel
    4. Geneva Research Center
    5. Cours
    - Sub-subseries III.C.1: Executive Committee Minutes, 1912 1925-1926 1934-1937
      - Scattered selection of minutes. 1912 minutes include meetings of the Advisory Council. (Box 105)
    - Sub-subseries III.C.2: Officers
      - a. Baron d'Estournelles de Constant (President of Advisory Council), 1911-1924 (2 boxes)
        Correspondence concerns formation of the Advisory Council, invitations to join the Advisory Council, France-Amerique Society, and administration of the Paris office, including finances, rentals, and purchases.
        - 1911-1912 April (Box 105)
        - 1912 June -1924 (Box 106)
      - b. Earle B. Babcock (Directeur-Adjoint), 1925-1935 (7 boxes)
        Correspondence concerns lectures, meetings of the Comité du Centre Européen, Professorships, Chaire Carnegie, the Library of the Centre Européen, conferences, International Studies Conference, International Trade Conference, International Consultive Group, and the death of Earle B. Babcock.
        - 1925 Jan-June (Box 106)
        - 1925 July -1926 May (Box 107)
        - 1926 Sept-1927 (Box 108)
        - 1928-1930 May (Box 109)
        - 1930 June 1932 Feb (Box 110)
        - 1932 March-1933 (Box 111)
        - 1934-1935 Feb (Box 112)
      - c. Malcolm W. Davis (Directeur-Adjoint), 1935-1942 (6 boxes)
        Correspondence concerns the formation of an advisory council in Great Britain, International Peace Campaign, YMCA, Comité meetings, International Student Service, visiting American professors, International People’s College, wartime financing of Paris office, protection of Endowment property during the war.
        - 1935-1936 Feb (Box 113)
        - 1936 March-Dec (Box 114)
        - 1937 Jan-Oct (Box 115)
        - 1937 Nov-1939 Feb (Box 116)
        - 1939 March-Dec (Box 117)
        - 1940-1942 (Box 118)
      - d. Mme. M. Perreux (Secretaire Generale), 1944-1949 (2 boxes)
        Correspondence concerns postwar reconstruction (Reims and Louvain), finances of Paris Office, closing of Paris office, French versions of Special Correspondent’s reports.
        - 1944-1947 (Box 118)
        - 1948-1949 (Box 119)
    - Sub-subseries III.C.3: Representatives and Associated Personnel, 1916-1948
      (11 boxes)
      This subseries consists the Endowment's correspondence with members of the Advisory Council, Comité, and the Special Correspondents. It also includes some special correspondents' reports.
      For special correspondent's reports see also I.N. and III.B. Topical Volumes. Reports.
      - Altamira y Creva, Rafael (Comité), 1938 (Box 119)
      - Bonn, Moritz J. (Comité), 1929 1930 1936 1937 (Box 119)
      - Cole, Percival R. (Special Correspondent, Australia)
        - 1930-1943 (Box 119)
        - 1944-1947 (Box 120)
      - Collins, William J. (Conseil d’Honneur, Special Correspondent, Great Britain), 1922-1930 (Box 120)
      - Efremoff, M. Jean (Advisory Council, Special Correspondent, Russia / U.S.S.R., Conseil d’Honneur)
        - 1923-1925 (Box 120)
        - 1926-1937 (Box 121)
        - 1938-1939 1944-1945 (Box 122)
      - Foerster, F.W. (Special Correspondent, Germany, Conseil d’Honneur), 1923-1929 (Box 122)
      - Gerlach, Hellmut von (Conseil d’Honneur, Advisory Council, Special Correspondent, Germany)
        - 1922-1924 (Box 122)
        - 1925-1930 (Box 123)
      - Giretti, Edoardo (Advisory Council, Conseil d’Honneur, Special Correspondent, Italy)
        - 1923-1932 (Box 123)
        - 1933-1938 (Box 124)
      - Godart, Justin (Comité), 1925 (Box 124)
      - Hirst, Francis W. (Special Correspondent, Great Britain), 1929 1935 1938 1946 (Box 124)
      - Lange, Christian L. (Special Correspondent, Geneva), 1919-1933 (Box 124)
      - Lechartier, M. Georges (Comité), 1927-1938 (Box 125)
      - Lichtenberger, Henri, 1925-1926 (Box 125)
      - MacDonald, Ramsay, 1911 1925 1935 (Box 125)
      - Mensdorff, Albert von (Comité), 1927 (Box 125)
      - Misciatelli, Piero (Comité), 1927-1937 (Box 125)
      - Mitrany, David (Special Correspondent, England), 1927-1929 (Box 125)
      - Miyaoka, Tsunejiro (Special Correspondent, Japan, Conseil d’Honneur)
        - 1917-1918 1922-1924 June (Box 125)
        - 1924 July -1929 April (Box 126)
        - 1929 June -1931 (Box 127)
        - 1933-1934 1937 1943-1948 (Box 128)
      - Nippold, Otfried (Conseil d’Honneur, Special Correspondent, Germany)
        - 1923 (Box 128)
        - 1924-1926 1930 1932 (Box 129)
      - Oka, Minoru, 1922 (Box 129)
      - Paszkowski, Wilhelm (Special Correspondent), 1916-1921 (Box 129)
      - Prittwitz un Gaffron, Eric von (Comité), 1926-1939 1947 (Box 129)
      - Redlich, Josef, 1921-1923 (Box 129)
      - Stannard, Harold (Special Correspondent, Great Britain), 1935-1939 (Box 129)
      - Venizelos, E.K. (Advisory Council), 1923 (Box 129)
    - Sub-subseries III.C.4: Geneva Research Center, 1932-1939
      (4 folders)
      The Geneva Research Center, partially supported by the European Centre, was under the administration of an international governing board and afforded opportunities to young scholars for work on special subjects. The Center also carried on inquiries for the International Studies Conference and other international organizations for scientific study, published a series of Geneva Studies on selected subjects, and issued a monthly Information Bulletin on developments and events as seen from Geneva on activities of the League of Nations and the International Labor Organization. (Source: Carnegie Endowment for International Peace: Summary of Organization and Work. Washington DC: CEIP, 1941 p28.)
      - This subseries contains requests for funds, reports, and meeting minutes, as well as correspondence concerning the Geneva Institute of International Relations and the Geneva News Letter. (Box 30)
    - Sub-subseries III.C.5: Cours, 1928-1939
      (49 boxes)
      From 1926 through 1939 in collaboration with the Institut des Hautes Études Internationales and under the auspices of the Faculty of Law in the University of Paris, the Centre Européen conducted courses of lectures on international organization and relations. Starting in 1928 the Centre offered a considerable number of shorter courses in which cooperation was obtained from various faculties of schools in Paris. The lectures were published and distributed to libraries in Europe and the United States.
      This subseries consists of the typescripts and page proofs of these lectures.
      - Allier, Raoul. Les églises de la réforme et le probleme de la paix au cours du XIXe siecle, 1931 (Box 130)
      - Ancel, Jacques
        - Géographie politique-Les balkans, 1927-1928 (Box 131)
        - Géographie politique-Les frontieres de L'Allemagne, Feb 10, 1932-May 4, 1932
          - L'Allegmagne: l'etat et la nation (Box 131)
          - La prusse orientale (Box 131)
          - La ville libre de Dantzig (Box 131)
          - Le pomorze (corridor polonais) (Box 131)
          - La haute Silesi (Box 131)
          - La front allemand de la Boheme (Box 131)
          - La frontiere des Alpes (Box 131)
          - L'Anschluss (Box 131)
          - La frontiere du Rhin (Box 131)
          - Les confins occidentaux (Box 131)
        - Géographie politique-Les frontieres de l'Europe centrale, Nov 8, 1933-Jan 17, 1934 (Box 132)
        - Géographie politique
          - 1934 Nov 7-1935 Feb 6 (Box 132)
          - 1935 Nov 13-1936 Feb 12 (Box 132)
          - 1936 Nov 18-1937 Feb 24 (Box 133)
        - Géographie politique et economique, 1937 Nov 17-1938 Feb 9 (Box 133)
      - Barthelemy, Joseph. La politique exterieure dans les democraties, 1929 Dec 5-1930 Jan 23 (Box 133)
      - Basdevant, 1928
        - Bourgeois, Emile (Box 133)
        - 1929
          - L'Europe et le probleme mediterraneen 1871-1930 (Box 133)
          - 1931 March6 (Box 133)
          - 1931 March23: L'Angleterre et le France en mediterranee, Suex, Chypre, et la Tunisie (Box 133)
          - 1931 March: La question d'Egypte (Box 133)
          - 1931 March: La Italie (Box 133)
          - 1931 April: La ligue mediterraneene de 1887 (Box 133)
          - 1931 April :: La decadence de la Turquie, L'Italie, et la Greece (Box 133)
          - 1931 May 1: La cote africaine de la mediterrane le Maroc et l'Algerie (Box 133)
          - Les crises de la mediterranee orientale (Box 133)
          - La mediterranee pendant la Grande (Box 133)
          - 1931 May 22 (Box 133)
          - First three lessons (Box 133)
          - First eight lessons (Box 133)
          - Last two lessons (Box 133)
        - 1931 Nov 20: Les Detroits: geographie et histoire (Box 134)
        - 1931 Nov 17: Les conventions des Detroits de 1798-1808 (Box 134)
        - 1931 Dec 4: Le traite Angle-Turc et la convention des detroits de 1809 (Box 134)
        - 1931 Dec 11: Les traites d'unklar skelseei et se londres (Box 134)
        - 1931 Dec 18: Dela convention des Detroits de 1841 au traite de Paris 1856 (Box 134)
        - 1932 Jan 8: La neutralisation de la mer noire (Box 134)
        - 1932 Jan 15: La conference de Londres (Box 134)
        - 1932 Jan 22: La question des detroits au traite de Berlin (Box 134)
        - 1932 Jan 29: La question des detroits dans la politique internationale sous le regne d'Abdul-Hamed (Box 134)
        - 1932 Feb 5: Politique Allemande et Russe aux detroits avant et pendant la Guerre Mondial (1897-1917) (Box 134)
        - 1932 Feb 12: Les dernieres conventions des detroits: Sevres 1920 et Lausanne 1923 (Box 134)
        - Histoire Diplomatique 1815-1870 1932-1933 (Box 134)
      - Briere, R.P. de la
        - 1929 Jan-Feb (Box 134)
        - 1929 March-April (Box 135)
        - 1931 Feb 3: Allocutionde M. Lechartier (Box 135)
        - 1931 Feb 10: Leon XIII et le premiere conference de la paix en 1899 (Box 135)
        - 1931 Feb 24-1931 Mar 17 (Box 135)
      - Chklaver
        - Le droit des gens correspondant aux nouvelles formes de l'etat, Dec 9, 1936-Dec 23, 1936 (Box 135)
        - Doctrines contemporaines de droit international, Jan 5, 1938-Feb 2, 1938 (Box 135)
        - Les principes du droit international moderne, Jan 4, 1939-Feb 1, 1939 (Box 135)
      - De Lapradelle
        - 1928 Nov 13-1929 April 16 (Box 136)
        - 1929 April 23-June 11 (Box 137)
        - Droit international publique
          - 1931 Nov 17-1932 April 5 (Box 137)
          - 1932 April 12-1932 May 24 (Box 138)
          - 1932 Nov 8-1933 May 9 (Box 138)
          - 1933 Nov 7-1934 May 29 (Box 139)
          - 1934 Nov 6-1935 May 21 (Box 140)
        - Principes généraux du droit international publique, Nov 18, 1930-Jun 2, 1931
          - 1930 Nov 18-1931 Jan 20 (Box 140)
          - 1931 Jan 27-June 2 (Box 141)
        - Principes generaux du droit des gens
          - 1935 Nov 12-1936 Jan 21 (Box 141)
          - 1936 Jan 28-May 19 (Box 142)
      - de Monftort. La Finlande, charniere entre les Scandinaves et les Baltes, 1939 Feb 8-1939 Mar 8 (Box 142)
      - Deak, Francis. La neutralite, 1937 Nov 23-1937 Dec 20 (Box 142)
      - Dennery
        - Problemes Economique Contemporains, 1932 Nov 18-1933 Feb 17 (Box 142)
        - Geographie economique: Les conflicts politiques contemporains et leurs causes economiques, 1933 Nov 14-1934 May 8 (Box 143)
        - Geographie economique
          - 1935 Feb 19-1935 May 15 (Box 144)
          - 1936 Feb 19-1936 May 20 (Box 144)
          - 1938 Feb 23-1938 May 18 (Box 144)
          - 1939 Feb 22-1939 May 31 (Box 144)
      - Dimitroff. La Bulgarie, le probleme de la thrace et l'acces a la mer egee, and Les differents aspects du probleme thracies depuis le traite de San-Sthephano jusqu'a nos jours (Box 145)
      - Dolleans, Edouard
        - L'action des cartels et la structure d'une economie internationale, 1936 May 8-1936 May 29 (Box 145)
        - L'organisation internationale des transports et de la production, 1937 April 23-1937 May 21 (Box 145)
      - Dupuis, Charles
        - Les grandes systémes de politique internationale
          - 1927-1928 (Box 145)
          - 1928-1929 (Box 146)